很久以前在遥远的银河系
星   球   大   战
第九部  天行者崛起
亡者誓言 银河系听见了神秘的声音
已故帕尔帕廷皇帝发出阴险的复仇威胁
莱娅▪欧嘉纳将军派出间谍搜集情报
绝地武士的最后希望 蕾伊
则接受训练准备对抗凶残的第一军团
此外 最高领袖凯洛伦急寻皇帝的幽灵
决心排除任何有碍他权力的威胁
终于
At last.
斯努克将你训练得不错
Snoke trained you well.
我杀了斯努克
I killed Snoke.
也会杀了你
I'll kill you.
年轻人
My boy.
我造就了斯努克
I made Snoke.
我每个声音
I have been every voice...
都在你脑中听到的
you have ever heard inside your head.
第一军团只是开端
The First Order was just the beginning.
我会给你更多
I will give you so much more.
你会先死
You'll die first.
我以前曾经死过
I have died before.
原力的黑暗面是一条途径
The dark side of the Force is a pathway...
通往某些人认为
to many abilities some consider to be...
不自然的能力
unnatural.
你能给我什么
What could you give me?
一切
Everything.
一个新帝国
A new Empire.
强大的最终军团蓄势待发
The might of the Final Order will soon be ready.
只要遵照我的要求 它就是你的
It will be yours if you do as I ask.
杀了那个女孩
Kill the girl!
终结绝地武士
End the Jedi...
攀上你祖父维达无法企及的高峰
and become what your grandfather Vader could not.
你将统治整个银河系
You will rule all the galaxy...
成为新皇帝
as the new emperor.
但是注意
But beware...
她并非你所想的那样
she is not who you think she is.
那她是谁
Who is she?
你到底要不要动下一步
Are you ever gonna go?
他不可能每次都赢 显然可以
He can't beat us every time. Apparently he does.
他怎么做到的
How does he do it?
这家伙 因为他作弊
This guy right here? It's 'cause he cheats.
开玩笑的啦
I'm kidding!
- 轮到你了 - 你250岁了
- Oh, come on. Take your turn. - You're 250 years old.
拖拖拉拉就算作弊
You're taking forever. That's cheating.
你当然比较厉害
Of course you're better than us.
我们觉得你作弊
That's why we think you're cheating.
别担心 我们不会趁机关掉
Don't worry! We're not gonna turn it off.
他作弊 绝对是
He's cheating. Definitely.
克劳 希望你把突波修好了
Klaud, I hope you fixed that surge.
倒数五秒钟
T-minus five.
R2
Artoo.
布里欧 你好 有什么给我们吗
Boolio, good to see you. You got something for us?
来自一个新盟友 第一军团里的间谍
From a new ally! A spy in the First Order!
间谍 谁
A spy? Who?
不知道
I don't know!
转换讯息 交给莱娅 快
Transfer the message! Get it to Leia, hurry!
这可能是重大情报 R2
This could be big, Artoo.
锁定目标
Locked on target.
芬恩 我们要完蛋了
Finn, we're about to be cooked!
快好了
We're almost there!
波 搞定了
Poe, we got it.
我们该怎么谢你
How do we thank you?
打赢战争
Win the war!
对不起 我知道
Sorry, I'm sorry! I know!
芬恩 你应该能解决掉那些东西
Finn, you're supposed to be getting rid of those things!
干掉一架 还剩几架
I got one! How many are left?
太多了
Too many.
什么
What?
没错丘伊
Good thinking, Chewie.
芬恩 压垮这些钛战机
Finn, we can boulder these TIEs!
我刚刚也这么想
I was just thinking that.
带我们回基地
Get us back to base!
你想那道冰墙有多厚
How thick do you think that ice wall is?
波 我知道
Poe! I know, I know!
你在做什么
What are you doing?
光速跃进
Lightspeed skipping.
你怎么会
How do you know how to do that?
蕾伊不在这里 对吧
Yeah, well, Rey's not here, is she?
最后一次跃进 可能没下次了
Last jump, maybe forever.
抓稳了
Hold on!
与我同在
Be with me.
它们没与我同在
They're not with me. Ugh.
蕾伊
Rey.
要有耐心
Be patient.
我开始觉得不太可能
I'm starting to think it isn't possible...
听到过去绝地武士的声音
to hear voices of the Jedi who came before.
没有什么不可能
Nothing's impossible.
我要开始训练课程了
I'm gonna run the training course.
不
No!
加入我
Join me.
班 不
Ben, no!
你杀了他
You killed him!
班
Ben!
BB-8 真抱歉
BB-8, I'm so sorry.
我没完成训练课程
I didn't finish the training course.
一时分神
Got distracted.
我感觉不像自己
I'm just not feeling myself.
我知道看起来
I know it looks...
看起来像在找借口
It looks like I'm making excuses.
别说看起来如何
Don't tell me what things look like.
说出真实感受到的
Tell me what they are.
我想我只是累了 仅此而已
I think I'm just tired. That's all.
将军
General...
千年隼尚未抵达
the Falcon still hasn't arrived.
指挥官请求指示
Commander's asking for guidance.
我会配得上你哥的光剑
I will earn your brother's saber...
总有一天
one day.
不 这你无法帮上忙的
No, you can't do it for me.
千万别小看机器人
Never underestimate a droid.
是 大师
Yes, Master.
蕾伊
Rey!
千年隼回来了
Falcon's back!
快过来
Come on, get over here!
这里需要救火队
I need a fire crew here!
另一组去后面 快去
And another one in the back! Go, go!
来了
Coming!
起火了
It's on fire!
整个都起火了
Whole thing's on fire. All of it.
它起火了 嗨
It's on fire. Hey.
嗨 有间谍
Hey! There's a spy?
那里其实很需要你的帮忙
Really could have used your help out there.
情况如何
How'd it go?
非常糟糕 很糟糕
Really bad, actually. Really bad.
汉的船 你把机器人怎么了
Han's ship... What'd you do to the droid?
你把千年隼怎么了
What'd you do to the Falcon?
千年隼的状况比他好多了
The Falcon in a lot better shape than he is.
BB-8没起火
BB-8's not on fire.
剩下的部份没有
What's left of him isn't on fire.
告诉我怎么回事 你先说
Tell me what happened. You tell me first.
知道你怎样吗 怎样
You know what you are? What?
你很难搞 真的超难搞
You're difficult. Really difficult.
你是个难搞的男人 你是
You're a difficult man. You, you are...
- 蕾伊 - 芬恩
- Rey. - Finn. Oh.
你平安回来了
You made it back.
差点回不来
Yeah. Barely.
心情不好吗 我
So, bad mood? Me?
他 随时随地
Him. Always.
我们有间谍吗
Do we have a spy?
这个嘛
Well...
你用了光速跃进
You lightspeed skipped?
至少我们回来了 是吧
Yeah, well, it got us back here, didn't it?
波 压缩机坏了
Poe, the compressor's down.
我知道 我在场 又来了
Oh, I know, I was there. Every time.
千年隼不能用来光速跃进
You can't lightspeed skip the Falcon!
事实证明可以
Actually, it turns out you can.
好了 我们刚降落
All right, guys, we just landed, okay?
发生什么事
What happened?
收到坏消息
Bad news, that's what happened.
没有间谍
No spy?
不 有间谍
No. Spy.
我们到底有没有联系上一名间谍
Did we make contact with a spy or not?
第一军团有一名卧底
There's a mole in the First Order,
他们传来讯息
and they sent us a message.
你害他被一棵树砸到
You dropped a tree on him?
你炸毁了两台次交流发电机
You blew both sub-alternators?
你知道
Well, you know what...
也许你应该跟我们一起去
maybe you should've been out there with us!
你明知我想去
You know I wanna be out there with you.
但你没有
Yeah, but you're not.
你在这里受训 为了什么
You're here training. For what?
你是我们最优秀的飞行员
You're the best fighter we have.
我们需要你
We need you.
在那里 不在这里
Out there, not here.
小子
Junior...
带R2去修理
get Artoo into reconditioning.
真的
It's true.
那是什么讯息
What's the message?
我们解码了第一军团间谍提供的情报
We've decoded the intel from the First Order spy...
结果证实是最糟的状况
and it confirms the worst.
帕尔帕廷还是回来了
Somehow, Palpatine returned.
等等 这情报可信吗
Wait. Do we believe this?
不可能
It cannot be.
皇帝早死了
The Emperor is dead.
黑暗科学 复制
Dark science. Cloning.
只有西斯才知道的秘密
Secrets only the Sith knew.
他一直在密谋复仇
He's been planning his revenge.
他的追随者多年来都在集结
His followers have been building something for years.
建立银河系史上最庞大的舰队
The largest fleet the galaxy has ever known.
他称之为最终军团
He calls it the Final Order.
16小时后 整个自由世界将被攻击
In 16 hours, attacks on all free worlds begin.
皇帝和他的舰队一直躲在未知领域
The Emperor and his fleet have been hiding in the Unknown Regions.
一个叫厄西格的世界
On a world called Exegol.
厄西格没出现在任何星图上
Exegol does not appear on any star chart.
传说将它形容为西斯的隐蔽世界
But legend describes it as the hidden world of the Sith.
传言他不遗余力逃避死亡
There were always whispers of his hunger to cheat death.
所以帕尔帕廷始终在那里
So, Palpatine's been out there all this time.
幕后操控
Pulling the strings.
一向如此 打从开始就藏身阴影中
Always. In the shadows. From the very beginning.
如果要阻止他 就必须找到他
If we want to stop him, we must find him.
必须找到厄西格
Must find Exegol.
将军
General?
我能跟您谈一下吗
Can I speak with you?
我知道怎么到厄西格
I know how to get to Exegol.
说说看 卢克找过那地方
Tell me. Luke searched for it.
找了好久 差点就找到了
For a long time. He nearly found it.
这里有暗号我看不懂
There are ciphers here I can't read.
但他说需要这东西才能到达
But he said to get there, you need one of these.
西斯导航仪
A Sith wayfinder.
它们是罗盘 能带人前往厄西格
They're compasses that lead the way to Exegol.
要阻止即将来袭的那个敌人
To stop what we both know is coming...
我必须完成卢克的使命
I need to finish what Luke started.
找到皇帝
Find Exegol.
Find the Emperor.
不行
No.
就算没有您的支持 我也非去不可
I don't want to go without your blessing, but I will.
我会去
I will.
换作您也会这么做
It's what you would do.
你把它修好了
So, you got her up and running?
你说的对
You were right before.
我要接续卢克寻找厄西格的任务
I'm gonna pick up Luke's search for Exegol.
从他留下最后线索的地方开始
I'm gonna start where his trail went cold.
帕萨纳的禁闭荒漠
The Forbidden Desert of Pasaana.
我知道 我们跟你去
Yeah, I know. We're going with you.
丘伊 压缩机修好了吗
Chewie, you get that compressor fixed?
我必须单独前往
I need to go alone.
对 单独跟朋友前往
Yeah. Alone with friends.
这太危险了 芬恩
It's too dangerous, Finn.
我们一起去
We go together.
我百分之百认同
I wholeheartedly agree.
萝丝 最后的机会
Rose, last chance.
将军要我研究旧驱逐舰的规格
The General asked me to study the specs of old Destroyers.
如果你们找到 才能阻止舰队
So we can stop the fleet if you find it.
如果
"If"?
等我们找到
When.
我们该出发了
Hey, we should get going.
怎么了
What is it?
没事
Nothing.
要是我没回来
In the event that I do not return...
我希望你知道
I want you to know
你是真正的朋友 R2
that you have been a real friend, Artoo.
事实上是我最好的那个
My best one, in fact.
我有好多话想对您说
There's so much I want to tell you.
等你回来再说
Tell me when you get back.
蕾伊
Rey...
千万别害怕真实的自我
never be afraid of who you are.
是啊
It is.
伦武士团
Knights of Ren.
好吓人
Ghouls.
我们内部有间谍
We have a spy in our ranks...
刚传了讯息给抵抗势力
who just sent a message to the Resistance.
无论叛徒是谁 都阻止不了我们
Whoever this traitor is won't stop us.
有了我在厄西格见到的
With what I've seen on Exegol...
第一军团即将成为真正的帝国
the First Order is about to become a true Empire.
我出现似乎带来一股不安 赫斯将军
I sense unease about my appearance, General Hux.
因为面具吗
About the mask?
没有 长官 非常好
No, sir. Well done.
我喜欢
I like it.
恕我直言 厄西格上的这些盟友
Forgive me, sir, but these allies on Exegol...
听起来像是个邪教
they sound like a cult.
都是巫师和占卜师
Conjurers and soothsayers.
他们召唤了大批灭星者驱逐舰
They've conjured legions of Star Destroyers.
西斯舰队会让我们的资源增加万倍
The Sith fleet will increase our resources ten-thousandfold.
那种威力将纠正弑星者基地的错误
Such range and power will correct the error of Starkiller Base.
我们得增加兵力
We'll need to increase recruitments.
注入年轻新血
Harvest more of the galaxy's young.
这支舰队 算是赠礼吗
This fleet, what is it, a gift?
他要求什么回报
What is he asking for in return?
准备击溃任何反抗我们的世界
Prepare to crush any worlds that defy us.
我的武士和我去猎杀那个拾荒者
My knights and I are going hunting for the scavenger.
你确定是这里
You sure this is it?
这些是卢克主人留下的精确座标
These are the exact coordinates that Master Luke left behind.
这是什么
What is this?
埃齐埃齐祖先节
The Acky Acky Festival of the Ancestors.
这项庆典每42年才举行一次
This celebration occurs only once every 42 years.
运气真好
Well, that's lucky.
确实很好运
Lucky indeed.
这项节庆以五彩缤纷的风筝
This festival is known for both its colorful kites...
以及美味的甜点著称
and its delectable sweets.
我没见过这种场面
I've never seen anything like this.
我没见过这么难找的导航仪
I've never seen so few wayfinders.
这种人群里总是有第一军团巡逻兵
There's always random First Order patrols in crowds like these.
低调一点
So, keep your heads down.
丘伊
Chewie.
我们分开走 问问本地人知道什么
Let's split up. See what the locals know.
她说 "欢迎"
She is saying, "Welcome."
她叫南碧吉玛
Her name is Nambi Ghima.
好棒的名字 我是蕾伊
That's an excellent name. I'm Rey.
若知道你姓什么 她会很荣幸
She would be honored to know your family name, too.
我没有姓
I don't have one.
我就叫蕾伊
I'm just Rey.
帕尔帕廷要你死
Palpatine wants you dead.
- 你效忠另一个主人 - 不是
- Serving another master? - No.
我有别的计划
I have other plans.
我曾提供你一个共创大业的机会
I offered you my hand once.
你也想接受
You wanted to take it.
后来为何不接
Why didn't you?
当初你大可杀了我
You could've killed me.
为何没动手
Why didn't you?
你躲不掉的 蕾伊
You can't hide, Rey.
躲不了我
Not from me.
我看穿了你的面具
I see through the cracks in your mask.
你心神不宁
You're haunted.
不断看见你对你父亲下毒手
You can't stop seeing what you did to your father.
你还在计算父母离开了多久吗
Do you still count the days since your parents left?
你充满痛苦 愤怒
Such pain in you, such anger.
其实我不想杀你
I don't wanna have to kill you.
我会找到你
I'm going to find you
让你接受黑暗面
and I'm going to turn you to the dark side.
等我再次给你机会时
When I offer you my hand again...
你会接受
you'll take it.
等着瞧
We'll see.
你有看到他吗
Has he seen him?
我们该走了 快回千年隼
We have to go. Back to the Falcon. Now.
为什么 是凯洛伦
Why? It's Ren.
长官 我们分析过了
Sir, we've had this analyzed.
它来自米迪恩星系
It comes from the Middian System,
帕萨纳 禁闭谷
Pasaana, Forbidden Valley.
准备我的船
Prepare my ship.
通知当地部队 派出一个师
Alert the local troops. Send a division.
是 最高领袖
Yes, Supreme Leader.
不准动
Freeze.
站住
Hold it right there.
我发现抵抗势力逃犯
I've located the Resistance fugitives.
全体人员向
All units, report...
跟我走
Follow me.
快点
Hurry.
莱娅传了讯息给我
Leia sent me a transmission.
好
Okay.
你怎么找到我们的
How'd you find us?
武技族特别显眼
Wookiees stand out in a crowd.
我也很高兴见到你 老弟
It's good to see you too, old buddy.
这是蓝多卡瑞辛将军
This is General Lando Calrissian.
我们知道他是谁 3PO
We know who he is, Threepio.
幸会 将军
It is an honor, General.
卡瑞辛将军 我们在找厄西格
General Calrissian, we're looking for Exegol.
想当然
Of course you are.
总共只有两个
Only two were made.
西斯导航仪
A Sith wayfinder.
卢克天行者来这里找过
Luke Skywalker came here to find one.
我知道 我陪他来的
I know. I was with him.
卢克和我在跟踪一个老绝地武士猎人
Luke and I were tailing an old Jedi hunter.
贝斯图的奥奇
Ochi of Bestoon.
他带着能找到导航仪的线索
He was carrying a clue that could lead to a wayfinder.
我们横越银河系跟踪他的船到这里
We followed his ship halfway across the galaxy here.
追上时 船已遭废弃
When we got to his ship, it was abandoned...
没有线索 没有导航仪
No clue. No wayfinder.
奥奇的船还在这里吗
Is Ochi's ship still here?
他把它丢在荒漠里
It's out in the desert, where he left it.
我们得找到那艘船 再搜寻一次
We need to get to that ship. Search it again.
我有不祥的预感
I got a bad feeling about this.
奥奇的船在洛齐峡谷外头
Ochi's ship is out past Lurch Canyon.
去吧 谢谢将军
Go. Thank you, General.
你也是 丘伊
You too, Chewie.
莱娅需要飞行员 将军
Leia needs pilots, General.
我老早就不飞了
My flying days are long gone.
帮我一个忙
But do me a favor...
替我问候莱娅
give Leia my love.
你应该亲自问候她
You should give it to her yourself.
谢谢
Thank you.
那边 那些飞行器
There! Those speeders.
你怎么会
How do you know how to do that?
不必担心 我做的
No need to worry. I made it.
我们该走了
We gotta go.
我们发现逃犯
We've spotted the fugitives.
他们会飞了
Oh! They fly now!
They fly now?
他们会飞了
They fly now.
甩掉他们了吗
Did we lose them?
- 看来是 - 做得好 长官
- Looks like it! - Excellent job, sir!
做得不好 长官
Terrible job, sir!
现在别烦 BB-8
Not now, BB-8.
千万别小看机器人
Never underestimate a droid.
波
Poe!
正啊
Right, ho!
奥奇的船
Ochi's ship.
我见过那艘船
I've seen that ship before.
蕾伊
Rey!
全都解决掉了吗
You get all of them?
这是什么
What the hell is this?
下沉平原 设法抓住什么
Sinking fields! Try to grab something!
Will this agony ever end?
不会吧
Come on!
BB-8 不
BB-8! No!
蕾伊
Rey.
什么 芬恩
Rey, I never told you...
What? Finn!
将军
General.
我们收到消息 祖先节那边被袭击
We're getting reports of a raid at the Festival of Ancestors.
这项任务非常重要 不许失败
This mission is everything. We cannot fail.
有蕾伊的消息吗
Any word from Rey?
千年隼没有回应
Falcon's not responding.
你一定要讲成这样吗
Do you have to say it like that?
怎样
Like what?
帮我一个忙 乐观一点
Do me a personal favor? Be optimistic.
是
Yes, ma'am.
好极了
Uh, this is... This is terrific.
你不敢相信情况有多乐观
You're not gonna believe how well this is gonna turn out.
结果一定很棒
It's gonna be great.
蕾伊 芬恩
Rey! Finn!
你没叫我名字 但我没事
You didn't say my name, sir, but I'm all right.
你没事吧 嗯
You all right? Yeah.
芬恩呢
Where's Finn?
丘伊呢
Where's Chewie?
我没事
I'm good.
芬恩主人
Ah. Master Finn.
这是什么地方
What is this place?
这不是来生吧
This isn't the afterlife, is it?
机器人有来生吗
Are droids allowed here?
我以为我们完蛋了
I thought we were goners.
还是有可能
We might still be.
走哪条路出去
Which way out?
我们得赶快
We have to hurry.
- 所以是什么 - 什么
- So, what was it? - What?
你有话跟我说 什么时候
What you were gonna tell me? When?
你在沙地中下沉时 你说
When you were sinking in the sand, you said...
"我还没告诉你 "
"I never told you..."
晚点再跟你说
I'll tell you later.
等波不在的时候
You mean when Poe's not here?
对
Yeah. Mm-hmm.
我们要死在沙穴里了还搞神秘
We're gonna die in sand burrows and we're all keeping secrets?
等你先说你在玩什么把戏时我就说
I'll tell you when you tell us about all that shifty stuff you do.
我不想知道这些地道是什么做的
I do not wanna know what made these tunnels.
从地道壁的周长判断
Judging by the circumference of the tunnel walls...
我说我不想知道
I said I do not wanna know.
不想
Not.
那是什么
What's that?
- 飞行器吗 - 什么
- Is that a speeder? - What?
旧的
An old one.
或许我们会找到驾驶
Perhaps we will find the driver.
BB-8 我也这么想
Yep, BB-8, I think dead, too.
天啊 六角符
Oh, my. A hex charm.
什么
A what?
常见的西斯效忠者象征
A common emblem of Sith loyalists.
西斯
Sith.
这是奥奇的
This was Ochi's?
卢克的感觉是对的 奥奇没离开过这
Luke sensed it. Ochi never left this place.
他落脚在这里
And he ended up down here.
他要去找他的船
He was headed for his ship.
我们和他碰到同样的事
Same thing happened to us, happened to him.
奥奇怎么出去的
So, how did Ochi get out?
他没有出去
He didn't.
没错 他没有
No, he didn't.
骨头
Bones.
我不喜欢骨头
I don't like bones.
骨头 绝对不是好征兆
Bones? Never a good sign.
对 我看到了
Yeah, I see it.
可怕的事情
Horrible things...
曾跟这东西一起发生
have happened with this.
上面有写字
There's writing on it.
也许我能翻译
Perhaps I can translate.
导航仪的位置
Oh. The location of the wayfinder,
刻在这把匕首上
has been inscribed upon this dagger.
这是卢克大师在找的线索
It's the clue that Master Luke was looking for.
所以呢 导航仪在哪
And? Where's the wayfinder?
我恐怕不能告诉你们
I am afraid I cannot tell you.
你懂千兆种语言 看不懂吗
20.3 fazillion languages, you can't read that?
我看得懂 先生
Oh, I have read it, sir.
我知道导航仪的正确位置
I know exactly where the wayfinder is.
可惜它是用西斯的卢恩语言写的
Unfortunately, it is written in the runic language of the Sith.
又怎样
So what?
我的程式禁止我翻译它
My programming forbids me from translating it.
难得要你发表意见 你却没办法
So, you're telling us the one time we need you to talk, you can't?
真讽刺 先生
Irony, sir.
我的构造无法说出西斯文翻译
I am mechanically incapable of speaking translations from Sith.
我想规则是由
I believe the rule was passed
旧共和国参议会通过
by the Senate of the Old Republic...
有蛇 有蛇啊
Serpent! Serpent! Serpent!
蕾伊
Rey.
芬恩
Finn. Shh.
我要轰了它 不要
I'm gonna blast it. Don't blast it.
我只是传递了一点生命力
I just transferred a bit of life.
给了它原力能量
Force energy from me to him.
你也会这么做
You would've done the same.
我们不可能搭那艘破东西飞行
We cannot possibly fly in that old wreck.
我们得继续前进
We gotta keep moving.
去找能翻译匕首文字的人
Find someone who can translate that dagger.
帮得上忙的机器人
Like a helpful droid.
我建议我们马上回到千年隼
I suggest we return to the Millennium Falcon at once.
他们会在千年隼等我们
They'll be waiting for us at the Falcon.
抓我们去喂虫
Yeah, they'll throw us in the Pits of Griq.
对 把你当标靶机器人
Yeah. And use you as a target droid.
你们都说得很有道理 有时候
You both make excellent points, at times.
怎么了
What is it?
我马上来
I'll be right behind you.
没关系
It's okay.
看看有什么可用
Let's see what we got.
启动那些转换器
Let's get those converters fired up.
好脏的一艘船
What a filthy ship!
你们看
Look at that.
她在哪里
Where is she?
芬恩 过来帮我
Finn, help me out over here.
丘伊 跟蕾伊说我们该走了
Chewie, tell Rey we gotta go.
她在做什么
What's she doing?
丘伊跑哪去了
Where the hell's Chewie?
是凯洛伦
It's Ren.
好 走吧
All right, let's go.
上去
Get in the transport.
快走 怪物
Move, animal!
蕾伊
Rey!
他们抓走丘伊 他们抓走他了
They got Chewie! They got him!
丘伊
Chewie!
不
No!
蕾伊
Rey!
我们快走 他们来了
We gotta go! They're coming!
蕾伊 快点
Rey, come on!
蕾伊
Rey!
该走了 丘伊
We gotta go! Chewie.
蕾伊 快点
Rey, come on!
我失控了
I lost control.
不是你的错
It wasn't your fault.
是
It was.
不 是凯洛伦 是他逼迫你
No. It was Ren. He made you do it.
丘伊死了
Chewie's gone.
那是从我身上产生的力量
That power came from me.
芬恩 有些事你不知道
Finn, there are things you don't know.
那就告诉我
Then tell me.
我看到一个景象
I, uh, had a vision.
Of the throne of the Sith.
还有坐在上面的人
And who was on it.
凯洛伦
Ren?
和我
And me.
我们发现拾荒者的船
We recovered the scavenger's ship,
但她逃走了
but she got away.
在伦武士团的指挥下
Under command of the Knights of Ren,
我们伤亡惨重
we suffered losses.
- 一艘运输船被毁 - 我看过报告
- A transport was destroyed. - I've seen the report.
就这样
That all?
还有 忠诚将军
No, Allegiant General.
荒漠中有另一艘运输船
There was another transport in the desert.
它载回一名重要的囚犯
It brought back a valuable prisoner.
囚犯
Prisoner?
以前常和汉索罗一起飞行的野兽
The beast used to fly with Han Solo.
带它到六号侦讯室
Take it to Interrogation Six.
快走
Move it.
我们只剩八小时
We've only got eight hours left.
怎么办
So, what are we gonna do?
能怎样办 我们得回基地去
What can we do? We gotta go back to base.
来不及回去 我们不能放弃
We don't have time to go back. We are not giving up.
否则丘伊就会白白牺牲
If we do that, Chewie died for nothing.
波 匕首在丘伊身上
Poe, Chewie had the dagger!
我们想别的办法
Well, then we gotta find another way.
没别的办法
Well, there isn't. That was the only clue
那是导航仪的唯一线索 现在没了
to the wayfinder thing, and it's gone.
真的
So true.
刻文现在只在我的记忆里
The inscription lives only in my memory now.
等一下
Hold on.
匕首上的刻文在你的记忆里
The inscription that was on the dagger is in your memory?
是 波主人
Yes, Master Poe.
但禁忌语言的翻译
But the translation from a forbidden language
无法取得
cannot be retrieved.
就差完整的已编辑记忆旁路
That is short of a complete redacted memory bypass.
完整的什么
A complete what?
是一个人渣和罪犯才做得出
It's a terribly dangerous and sinful act...
对无辜机器人的邪恶行径
performed on unwitting droids by dregs and criminals.
就这么办
Let's do that.
我认识黑市的机器人工匠
I know a black market droidsmith.
黑市机器人工匠
Black market droidsmith?
他在奇基米星 奇基米星有什么问题吗
But he's on Kijimi. What's wrong with Kijimi?
我在奇基米星走衰运
I had a little bad luck on Kijimi.
但若任务失败 就会落得一场空
But if this mission fails, it's all been for nothing.
这段时间的努力都白费了
All we've done, all this time.
我们大家全力以赴
We're all in this.
坚持到底
Until the end.
为了丘伊
For Chewie.
一言为定
Hands?
为了丘伊
For Chewie.
去奇基米星
Kijimi.
电池充电完成
Battery charged.
你好
Hello.
- 你好 - 不 不 谢谢
- Hello. - No... No, thank you.
看来有人亏待过他
Looks like someone treated him badly.
没关系 现在你跟着我们
It's all right. You're with us now.
UATT步行机巡逻队前往60大道
U-A-T-T walker patrol, head down thoroughfare 60.
开门 你们必须接受调查
Open up. You're wanted for questioning.
查看街道这边
Check this side of the street.
门上锁了
Door is locked.
移往下一道门
Move on to the next one.
请定时回报
Give me regular reports, please.
你 靠在墙上
You, up against the wall.
出示证件
Show me your identification.
你的证件呢
Where is your identification?
到处都是他们的人
They're everywhere.
拜托放了她 她什么都没做
Please, leave her alone. She didn't do anything.
好 我知道该怎么做
All right, I know what we should do.
我也是 我们应该离开了
So do I. We should leave.
闭嘴 3PO
Clam it, Threepio.
跟我走
Follow me.
好 我们往这边走
All right. Let's head down this way.
听说你出现在僧侣之门
Heard you were spotted at Monk's Gate.
我想 "他不会蠢到跑回来吧"
Thought, "He's not stupid enough to come back here."
超乎你想像
Oh, you'd be surprised.
这是谁 怎么回事
Who's this? What's going on?
这是佐丽 佐丽 这是蕾伊和芬恩
Guys, this is Zorii. Zorii, this is Rey and Finn.
我现在就能扣下扳机
I could pull this trigger right now.
我见过你更狠 而且报酬更少
I've seen you do worse. For a lot less.
我们能 谈一谈吗
Can we just, uh... talk about this?
我想看到你脑袋开花
I wanna see your brains in the snow.
你还在生气吗
So, you're still mad?
佐丽 我们需要你帮忙
Zorii, we could use your help.
尽快撬开这机器人的脑袋
We gotta crack this droid's head open and fast.
你说什么
Pardon me!
我们想找巴布佛利克
We're trying to find Babu Frik.
巴布 巴布只跟队友合作
Babu? Babu only works with the crew.
你已经不是队友了
That's not you anymore.
什么队友
What crew?
他竟然没提过
Oh, funny he never mentioned it.
你们朋友以前走私香料
Your friend's old job was running spice.
你当过香料走私贩
You were a spice runner?
你当过风暴兵 你走私香料
You were a stormtrooper? Were you a spice runner?
你当过拾荒者 这样没完没了
Were you a scavenger? We could do this all night.
没时间让你们拌嘴
You don't have all night.
我还在努力摆脱你造成的下场
You know, I'm still digging out of the hole you put me in
当时你跑去加入抵抗势力
when you left to join the Resistance.
你
You.
你就是他们在找的人
You're the one they're looking for.
她的赏金可能够我们还债
Bounty for her just might cover us.
攻击 别攻击
Djak'kankah! Don't djak'kankah.
我们真的需要你帮忙
We could really use your help.
拜托
Please.
你们大概都不在乎
Not that you care...
但我希望你是特例
but I think you're okay.
我在乎
I care.
T18上线了吗
T-18's online yet?
是 搜索周边
Yes, sir. Scouting the perimeter.
是步行机 跟紧一点
Walkers. Stay close by.
波戴姆伦 香料走私贩 走私香料
Poe Dameron, spice runner. Runner of spice.
- 好啦 - 快去抢香料
- All right. - Get your spice!
快点 3PO
Come on, Threepio.
巴布在后面
Babu's in the back.
别理我们
Don't mind us.
我一点都想不通为何要同意
I haven't the faintest idea why I agreed to this.
我一定是故障了
I must be malfunctioning.
巴布佛利克
Babu Frik?
你能帮我们这个忙吗
Can you help us with this?
佐丽 这行得通吗
Zorii? Is this gonna work?
他说在机器人的禁忌记忆库有所发现
He says he's found something in your droid's forbidden memory bank.
从西斯文翻译过来的文字
Words, translated from Sith.
就是那个 正是我们需要的
That's it. Yeah, that's what we need.
你们有认识会说西斯语的人吗
Who are you hanging out with that speaks Sith?
你能让他
Can you make him...
巴布 你能让他翻译出来吗
Babu, can you make him translate it?
可以 但那会造成完全
Yes. But it will cause a complete...
完全记忆清除
A complete memory wipe.
等等 等一下 我们让他翻译
Wait, wait, wait. We make him translate it...
他什么都不会记得
he won't remember... anything?
机器人 记忆变空白
Droid, memory go blank.
空白 空白
Oh! Blank, blank.
一定有别的办法
There must be some other way.
R2的储存单元以不可靠出名
Doesn't Artoo back up your memory?
拜托
Oh, please.
R2的储存单元以不可靠出名
Artoo's storage units are famously unreliable.
你比我们更清楚机率有多高
You know the odds better than any of us.
我们有选择吗
Do we have a choice?
如果这项任务失败
If this mission fails...
所有的努力就白费了
it was all for nothing.
这段时间以来 我们的一切努力
All we've done...all this time.
你在做什么 3PO
What are you doing there, Threepio?
好好地看我的朋友们
Taking one last look, sir...
最后一眼
at my friends.
好难过
Sad.
夜间突袭即将开始
Night raids are gonna start soon.
我先继续看守 我跟你去
I'll keep lookout. I'm coming with you.
你还是不信任我
You still don't trust me, huh?
那你信任过我吗
Did you ever trust me?
没有
Nope.
回报 普莱德将军
Report, General Pryde.
有新发展 长官
There's been a development, sir.
伦武士团追踪那个拾荒者
The Knights of Ren have tracked the scavenger.
到一个叫奇基米的移居地
To a settlement called Kijimi.
我们该摧毁那座城市吗
Shall we destroy the city,
最高
Supreme...?
我刚想到能试另一个办法
I just had an idea. There's something else we could try.
这样多久了
How long's it been like this?
第一军团很久以前带走大部份小孩
First Order took most of the kids a long time ago.
我再也受不了哭闹声
Can't stand the cries anymore.
我存了足够的钱逃出来
I've saved up enough to get out.
我要去殖民区
I'm going to the Colonies.
怎么去 超航道全都封锁了
How? All those hyperlanes are blocked.
这是第一军团的上尉勋章
That's a First Order Captain's medallion.
我没见过真的
I've never seen a real one.
能自由通过任何路障
Free passage through any blockade.
降落特权 登上任何船舰
Landing privileges, any vessel.
想跟我走吗
Wanna come with me?
我不能放下这场战争不管
I can't walk out on this war.
除非它结束
Not till it's over.
也许它结束了
Maybe it is.
我们在科瑞特战役时发出求救讯号
We sent out a call for help at the Battle of Crait.
没有人来
Nobody came.
大家都太害怕了
Everyone's so afraid.
他们放弃了
They've given up.
我不相信你这么想
No, I don't believe you believe that.
嘿
Hey.
让你以为自己孤立无援 他们就赢了
They win by making you think you're alone.
记得吗
Remember?
我们还有更多人
There's more of us.
轮子吱吱响
Squeaky wheel.
我的轮子吱吱响
I have a squeaky wheel.
吱吱响已清除
Squeak eliminated.
谢谢
Thank you.
真好心
Very kind.
这一切有点不对劲
Something's not right about all of this.
感觉似曾相识
I know where I've seen it.
他搭的船 奥奇的船
The ship he was on. Ochi's ship.
什么
What?
我父母离开那天
The day my parents left.
他们在那艘船上
They were on that ship.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
有驱逐舰接近
There's an incoming Destroyer.
我们该走了 搞定了吗 巴布
We gotta go now. Did we get it? Babu?
是 机器人准备就绪
Yep. Droid is ready!
皇帝的导航仪在帝国宝库里
The Emperor's wayfinder is in the Imperial vault.
在D36 瞬变936 方向32
At delta 3-6, transient 9-3-6, bearing 3-2...
位于恩多星系的一颗卫星上
on a moon in the Endor system.
来自南岸
From the southern shore.
唯有这刀锋能透露
Only this blade tells.
恩多星系
The Endor system.
上一场战争结束的地方
Where the last war ended?
蕾伊
Rey!
凯洛伦的驱逐舰
Ren's Destroyer.
他来了
He's here?
丘伊
Chewie?
他怎么样
What about him?
他在凯洛伦的船上
He's on Ren's ship.
他没死
He's alive.
什么 怎么会
What? How?
他没死 一定在不同的运输船上
He's alive! He must've been on a different transport.
我们得去找他
We gotta go get him.
你朋友在那太空垃圾上
Your friend's on that sky trash?
我猜是
I guess he is.
容我自我介绍
Might I introduce myself.
我是C3PO 公关机器人 你们是
I am C-3PO, human-cyborg relations. And you are?
这会是个问题
Okay, that's gonna be a problem.
你好 我巴布佛利克
Hello. I Babu Frik.
你好啊
Why, hello!
3PO 移动你的金属屁屁 快到了
Threepio, move your metal ass. We're almost there.
大胆 我们才刚认识
How dare you! We've only just met.
波
Poe.
它能让你登上主力舰
Might get you on a capital ship.
快去救你的朋友
Go help your friend.
佐丽 我觉得我不能拿
Zorii, I don't think I can take this.
我不管你怎么想
I don't care what you think.
我们该走了 快
We have to go. Now.
- 跟我们走 - 波
- Come with us. - Poe.
我能吻你吗
Can I kiss you?
快走
Go.
别轻举妄动
No sudden moves.
那是什么 别动
What is that? Stop moving.
勋章可以用
Medallion's good.
获准进入12号机库
Clear for entrance into hangar 12.
撑着点 丘伊
Hang on, Chewie.
我们马上来
We're coming.
不管丘伊是谁 这太扯了
Whoever this Chewie person is, this is madness!
出示文件和名单
Credentials and manifest.
- 你们三个待在那里 - 很乐意
- You three, stay there. - Happily.
哪个方向
Which way?
不知道 跟我走
Uh, no idea. Follow me.
放下武器
Drop your weapons.
我们在这里没关系
It's okay that we're here.
你们在这里没关系
It's okay that you're here.
没事
It's good.
你们很开心我们来了
You're relieved that we're here.
幸好你们来了
Thank goodness you're here.
欢迎各位
Welcome, guys.
她平常也这样对我们吗
Does she do that to us?
我们在找一名囚犯和他的物品
We're looking for a prisoner and his belongings.
监视器
The cameras.
他们说丘伊在这边
They said Chewie's this way.
蕾伊 快点
Rey, come on.
匕首在这艘船上 我们需要它
The dagger is on this ship. We need it.
怎么说
Why?
感觉 我到机库跟你们碰头
A feeling. I'll meet you back at the hangar.
蕾伊 你不能
Rey, you can't just...
去找丘伊
Chewie.
再次搜索全市
Search the city again.
她在附近
She's close.
我们当然是来救你的 丘伊
Of course we came for you, Chewie.
蕾伊也来了 她去找匕首
Yeah, Rey's here. She's gonna get the dagger.
这是谁的船
Whose ship is this?
船在这边 跟我走
The ship's this way. Follow me.
他们在这边
Over here!
走错了
Wrong way!
其实没有正确的路径吧
There's not really a right way, is there?
我发现他们了
I found them.
射杀他们
Blast them!
在这边
Over here!
快到了吗 直走
There they are. Get them!
We close? Straight ahead.
射杀他们
Blast them!
站住
Halt!
波
Poe!
你还好吗
Are you okay?
不好
Nope.
你们 手举高
You there, hands up!
立刻放下武器
Drop your weapons now!
放下武器
Put your weapons down!
放下
Drop them!
立刻放下
Drop them now!
你们好
Hey, fellas.
闭嘴 人渣
Shut up, scum.
不
No!
No.
蕾伊
Rey.
无论你在哪里
Wherever you are...
你实在很难找
you are hard to find.
摆脱掉你也很难
You're hard to get rid of.
我在荒漠里逼你
I pushed you in the desert,
因为我需要看到
because I needed to see it.
我需要你看到
I needed you to see it.
你的本性
Who you are.
我知道你其他的经历
I know the rest of your story.
蕾伊
Rey.
你说谎
You're lying.
我从来没骗过你
I never lied to you.
你的父母平凡无奇
Your parents were no one.
那是他们的选择
They chose to be.
希望你平安
To keep you safe.
你还记得你说
You remember more than you say.
我一直在你的脑中
I've been in your head.
我不要这样
I don't want this!
搜寻你的记忆
Search your memories.
不
No!
记住他们
Remember them.
看见他们
See them.
亲爱的 蕾伊 要勇敢
My love. Rey, be brave.
你在这里会很安全
You'll be safe here.
我保证
I promise.
回来
Come back!
不要
No!
他们为了保护你才卖掉你
They sold you to protect you.
别说了
Stop talking.
蕾伊 我知道他们发生什么事
Rey, I know what happened to them.
快走
Move it.
忠诚将军
Allegiant General,
拾荒者没跟他们在一起
the scavenger is not with them.
带他们走 杀了他们
Take them away. Terminate them.
告诉我你在哪里
Tell me where you are.
你并不知道事实全貌
You don't know the whole story.
是帕尔帕廷下令带走你父母
It was Palpatine who had your parents taken.
他在找你
He was looking for you.
但他们不肯说出你的下落
But they wouldn't say where you were.
所以他下令杀人
So he gave the order.
她不在贾库星 她走了
She isn't on Jakku. She's gone.
不
No!
原来你在那里
So that's where you are.
你知道皇帝为何一心要你死
You know why the Emperor's always wanted you dead.
不知道
No.
我会去告诉你
I'll come tell you.
她在我的舱房 封锁全船
She was in my quarters. Lock down the ship.
其实
Actually...
我想亲自动手
I'd like to do this myself.
之前你要告诉蕾伊什么
What were you gonna tell Rey before?
还在想那件事
You still on that?
抱歉 时机不对吗
Oh, I'm sorry, is this a bad time?
现在不太适合 波
Yeah. Sort of is a bad time, Poe.
晚一点应该没办法讲了
Well, 'cause later doesn't really look like an option.
如果你想一吐为快
If you're gonna let something off your chest,
也许现在能
maybe now's not the worst time to...
我就是那个间谍
I'm the spy.
什么 你
What? You?
我们时间不多
We don't have much time.
我就知道
I knew it.
才怪
No, you did not.
你的任务编号多少
What's your operating number?
根本没这种语言
That's not even a language.
天啊 我的第一场雷射枪战
Oh, dear! My first laser battle.
其他人呢 他们还没回来
Where are the others? They haven't come back.
去找他们
Find them.
- 快去 - 是
- Go. - Yes.
前方有朋友
Friends ahead.
对 他们来了
Oh, yes, there they are!
BB-8 快点
BB-8, come on!
我关闭阻抗器 你们只有几秒钟
I'll shut down the impeders. You've got seconds.
她在那里
There she is.
她命真硬
She's a survivor.
等等
Wait. Wait.
射我手臂 快 什么
Blast me in the arm. Quick. What?
不然他们会知道
Or they'll know.
不
No!
你为什么帮我们
Why are you helping us?
我不在乎你们会不会赢
I don't care if you win.
我只要凯洛伦输
I need Kylo Ren to lose.
皇帝为何追杀我
Why did the Emperor come for me?
他为何要杀一个孩子
Why did he want to kill a child?
告诉我
Tell me.
因为他看见你的未来
Because he saw what you would become.
你不只拥有力量
You don't just have power.
你拥有他的力量
You have his power.
你是他的孙女
You're his granddaughter.
你出自帕尔帕廷家族
You are a Palpatine.
我母亲是维达的女儿
My mother was the daughter of Vader.
你父亲是皇帝之子
Your father was the son of the Emperor.
帕尔帕廷不知道
What Palpatine doesn't know
我们是原力的二元体 蕾伊
is we're a dyad in the Force, Rey.
两人实为一体
Two that are one.
我们联手杀了他 夺下王位
We'll kill him together and take the throne.
你知道你该怎么做
You know what you need to do.
你知道
You know.
我知道
I do.
让船稳下来
Hold her steady.
芬恩 动作快
Finn, move fast!
蕾伊
Rey!
快过来
Come on!
快点 我抓住你
Come on! I got you!
那是协同入侵 忠诚将军
It was a coordinated incursion, Allegiant General.
他们击退卫兵
They overpowered the guards
逼我带他们上船
and forced me to take them to their ship.
知道了
I see.
帮我接最高领袖
Get me the Supreme Leader.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
告诉他我们逮到间谍了
Tell him we found our spy.
我不懂他们为何没跟来
I don't know why they're not following us,
事有蹊跷
but I don't trust it.
起落架坏了 多严重
Landing gear's busted? How busted?
最重要的是导航仪 找到厄西格
All that matters is the wayfinder. Finding Exegol.
我们正在进行
That's what we're doing.
他杀了我母亲
He killed my mother.
还有我父亲
And my father.
我要找到帕尔帕廷
I'm going to find Palpatine...
杀死他
and destroy him.
蕾伊
Rey...
这不像你会说的话
that doesn't sound like you.
蕾伊 我了解你
Rey, I know you...
人们一直说他们了解我
People keep telling me they know me.
恐怕没人真的了解
I'm afraid no one does.
那个绝地武士学徒还活着
The Jedi apprentice still lives.
说不定你背叛了我
Perhaps you have betrayed me.
别逼我用舰队对付你
Do not make me turn my fleet against you.
我知道她去哪
I know where she's going.
她不会成为绝地武士
She'll never be a Jedi.
确保那不会发生
Make sure of it.
杀了她
Kill her.
那是什么
What... What is that?
它是死星
It's the Death Star.
一场古老战争中的恶地
A bad place from an old war.
我们要好多年才能找到导航仪
It's gonna take us years to find what we're looking for.
天啊
Oh, dear.
"唯有这刀锋能透露"
"Only this blade tells."
导航仪在那里
The wayfinder's there.
注意
Heads up.
降落得真难看
Rough landing.
我看过更差的 我看过更好的
I've seen worse. I've seen better.
你们是抵抗势力吗
Are you Resistance?
看情况
That depends.
我们收到巴布佛利克传来的讯息
We picked up a transmission from someone named Babu Frik.
巴布佛利克 他是我的老朋友
Babu Frik? Oh, he's one of my oldest friends.
他说你们会来
He said you'd come.
他说你们是最后希望
He said you were the last hope.
我们得去残骸那里
We have to get to that wreck.
里面有我们需要的东西
There is something inside there we need.
我能带你们走水路
I can take you there by water.
- 你有看到海的状况吗 - 不是现在
- Have you seen the water? - Not now.
太危险了
Too dangerous.
明天天亮出发
We can go first light tomorrow.
我们等不了那么久 没时间了
We can't wait that long. We don't have the time.
也没有选择
Or the choice.
我们修好那艘船
Let's get that ship fixed.
你们有备用零件吗
Do you have any spare parts?
有一些
Some.
- 我是珍娜 - 我是波
- I'm Jannah. - I'm Poe.
你好
Hello.
不 谢谢 不 谢谢
No, thank you. No, thank you.
不 谢谢
What a dreadful situation.
你们每天都像这样吗
Is every day like this for you people?
太夸张了
Madness.
我们有找过他的音量键吗
Did we ever find his volume control?
这是06 应该能用
It's an O-6, but should work.
谢谢
Thank you.
这是第一军团的零件
This is a First Order part.
西脊上有艘老巡航舰
There's an old cruiser on the west ridge.
从上面拆来的
Stripped for parts.
分配给我们的那艘
The one we were assigned to.
我们用来逃走的那艘
The one we escaped in.
等一下 你待过第一军团
Okay, wait. You were First Order?
非自愿
Not by choice.
我们小时候全被征召入伍
We were conscripted as kids. All of us.
我是TZ1719 风暴兵
I was TZ-1719. Stormtrooper.
FN2187
FN-2187.
你
You?
我不知道还有更多
I never knew there were more.
逃兵吗 我们全曾是风暴兵
Deserters? All of us here were stormtroopers.
我们在安捷岛之战发动叛变
We mutinied at the battle of Ansett Island.
他们叫我们射杀平民
They told us to fire on civilians.
我们不肯
We wouldn't do it.
我们放下武器
We laid our weapons down.
所有人 一整连
All of you? The whole company.
我根本不知道怎么发生的
I don't even know how it happened.
那不是一个决定 比较像
It wasn't a decision, really, it was like...
一种本能
An instinct.
感觉
Feeling.
一种感觉
A feeling.
原力
The Force.
原力带我来这里
The Force brought me here.
带我去找蕾伊 还有波
It brought me to Rey. And Poe.
说得好像你确定它是真的
You say that like you're sure it's real.
它是真的
It's real.
当时我并不确定
I wasn't sure then...
但现在确定了
but I am now.
怎么了 老弟
What is it, buddy?
什么叫你没看见她
What do you mean you haven't seen her?
她开走悬浮机
She took the skimmer?
她到底在想什么
What the hell was she thinking?
波 我们得去追她
Poe, we gotta go after her.
把千年隼修复
We'll get the Falcon fixed,
尽快赶过去
and get out there as fast as we can.
不 我们追不上
No, we're gonna lose her.
她丢下我们 难道要用游泳的吗
Look, she left us! What do you wanna do? Swim?
她不太对劲
She's not herself.
你不知道她在对抗什么
You have no idea what she's fighting.
你就知道吗
And you do?
对 我知道
Yeah, I do.
莱娅也知道
And so does Leia.
我不是莱娅
Well, I'm not Leia.
一点也没错
That's for damn sure.
芬恩
Finn.
还有另一架悬浮机
There's another skimmer.
不要惧怕真实的自我
Don't be afraid of who you are.
看看你自己
Look at yourself.
你想向我母亲证明你是绝地武士
You wanted to prove to my mother that you were a Jedi...
结果却证明了别的
but you've proven something else.
你无法回去找她
You can't go back to her now.
就像我也不能
Like I can't.
交给我
Give it to me.
黑暗面存在于我们的本性里
The dark side is in our nature.
屈服吧
Surrender to it.
交给
Give it...
我
to me.
唯一能到厄西格的路就是跟我去
The only way you're getting to Exegol is with me.
不
No!
莱娅知道必须完成什么事 R2
Leia knows what must be done, Artoo.
现在联系她儿子
To reach her son now...
将耗尽她仅剩的力气
will take all the strength she has left.
蕾伊
Rey!
不
No!
不 我们不能跟过去
No, we can't follow them!
我不能丢下她 不能过去
I can't leave her! We can't!
蕾伊
Rey!
班
Ben.
莱娅
Leia.
其实我想牵起你的手
I did want to take your hand.
班的手
Ben's hand.
再见 亲爱的公主
Goodbye, dear princess.
波 出事了
Poe, something's happened.
芬恩 这不能等
Finn. This can't wait.
我们必须见将军
We've gotta see the General.
她走了
She's gone.
丘伊
Chewie...
孩子
Hey, kid.
我想你 儿子
I miss you, son.
你儿子死了
Your son is dead.
不对
No.
凯洛伦死了
Kylo Ren is dead.
我儿子还活着
My son is alive.
You're just a memory.
你的记忆
Your memory.
回家来
Come home.
太迟了
It's too late.
她走了
She's gone.
你母亲走了
Your mother's gone.
但她支持的 她抗争的
But what she stood for, what she fought for...
并没有消失
that's not gone.
班
Ben.
我知道我该做什么
I know what I have to do...
却不知道有没有力量去做
but I don't know if I have the strength to do it.
你有
You do.
爸
Dad...
我知道
I know.
艾岱伦公主阻碍了我的计划
The Princess of Alderaan has disrupted my plan...
但她愚蠢的行为只是白费力气
but her foolish act will be in vain.
到厄西格来见我 普莱德将军
Come to me on Exegol, General Pryde.
我在古老战争为您效命
As I served you in the old wars,
现在也是
I serve you now.
派一艘船去他们知道的世界
Send a ship to a world they know.
烧了它
Let it burn.
最终军团开始
The Final Order begins.
她会来 她朋友也会跟来
She will come, her friends will follow.
是 皇帝
Yes, my lord.
水平稳定度维持在85%
Levels holding steady at 85%.
上尉
Captain.
奇基米星位于射程内 发射
Kijimi is in range. Fire.
奇基米星 怎么会
Kijimi? How?
从灭星者驱逐舰发射的
A blast from a Star Destroyer.
来自新西斯舰队的一艘船
A ship from the new Sith fleet.
由未知领域出发
Out of the Unknowns.
皇帝从厄西格派出一艘船
The Emperor sent a ship from Exegol.
这代表舰队的每艘船
Does that mean every ship in the fleet...
都有毁灭星球级的武器 那当然
Has planet-killing weapons. Of course they do.
全部都有
All of them.
这就是他完成计划的方法
This is how he finishes it.
你们听
Listen.
每个频率上都有
It's on every frequency.
"抵抗势力已亡
"The Resistance is dead.
西斯之火将全面燃烧
The Sith flame will burn.
各个世界 不投降就死
All worlds, surrender or die.
最终军团开始"
The Final Order begins."
莱娅任命你为代理将军
Leia made you acting general.
现在怎么办
What now?
老实说 我其实不知道
I gotta tell you, I don't really know...
如何做到
how to do this.
你的成就
What you did...
我还没准备好
I'm not ready.
我们当时也还没
Neither were we.
卢克 汉 莱娅 我
Luke, Han, Leia, me...
谁曾经准备好
Who's ever ready?
你们如何做到的
How'd you do it?
几乎一无所有却击败一个帝国
Defeat an empire with almost nothing.
我们有彼此
We had each other.
我们就是那样赢的
That's how we won.
别碰 那是我朋友的
Hey, don't touch that. That's my friend's.
抱歉 她不在吗
Sorry. She is gone?
对 她不在
Yeah, she's gone.
我不知道她去哪
I don't know where.
我想她
I miss her.
我也想她
I miss her, too.
你叫什么名字
So, what's your name?
我有事跟你谈
I gotta talk to you about something.
我无法单独完成
I can't do this alone.
我需要你与我共同指挥
I need you in command with me.
这个机器人有 谢谢 很感激
This droid has... Thank you. I appreciate that.
将军 将军
General. General.
这机器人有厄西格的大量情报
This droid has a ton of information about Exegol.
什么 锥脸仔 我叫D0
Wait, what? Cone-face? I am D-O.
抱歉 D0
Sorry, D-O.
他原本要跟贝斯图的奥奇去厄西格
He was going to Exegol with Ochi of Bestoon.
奥奇干嘛去那里
Why was Ochi going there?
把他从贾库星带走的女孩交给皇帝
To bring the little girl he was supposed to take from Jakku to the Emperor.
他要她活着
He wanted her alive.
绝地武士的武器应获得更多尊重
A Jedi's weapon deserves more respect.
天行者大师
Master Skywalker.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
我看见自己坐在黑暗王座上
I saw myself on the dark throne.
我不会让那种事发生
I won't let it happen.
我绝不离开这里 我要效法您的行为
I'm never leaving this place. I'm doing what you did.
我错了
I was wrong.
是恐惧让我留在这里
It was fear that kept me here.
你最怕什么
What are you most afraid of?
我自己
Myself.
因为你出自帕尔帕廷家族
Because you're a Palpatine.
莱娅也知道
Leia knew it, too.
她没告诉我
She didn't tell me.
她还训练我
She still trained me.
因为她看见你的灵魂
Because she saw your spirit.
你的心
Your heart.
蕾伊
Rey.
有些东西比血脉更强大
Some things are stronger than blood.
面对恐惧是绝地武士的天命
Confronting fear is the destiny of a Jedi.
你的天命
Your destiny.
如果你不面对帕尔帕廷
If you don't face Palpatine...
那就代表绝地武士的末日
it will mean the end of the Jedi.
这场战争将会失败
And the war will be lost.
我妹会希望你拥有一样东西
There's something my sister would want you to have.
莱娅的光剑
Leia's saber.
那是她受训的最后一夜
It was the last night of her training.
莱娅感应到儿子死在
Leia told me that she had sensed the death of her son
绝地之路终点
at the end of her Jedi path.
她将光剑交给我 说有一天
She surrendered her saber to me and said that one day...
它将再度被拿起
it would be picked up again...
被一个能完成她使命的人
by someone who would finish her journey.
如今上千世代皆进驻在你心中
A thousand generations live in you now.
但这是你的战役
But this is your fight.
你带两支光剑到厄西格
You'll take both sabers to Exegol.
我到不了那里
I can't get there.
我没有导航仪 我摧毁了凯洛伦的船
I don't have the wayfinder. I destroyed Ren's ship.
你有了你所需的一切
You have everything you need.
总共有两个
Two were made.
你好 我是C3PO 公关机器人
Oh, hello. I am C-3PO, human-cyborg relations.
你是
And you are?
什么
What?
如果有好麻吉 相信我会记得
Well, I am quite certain I would remember if I had a best friend.
你想放什么在我脑中
You want to put what in my head?
无论如何
Under no circumstances...
记忆修复完成
Memory restoration complete.
R2 你听到了吗
Artoo, have you heard?
我要陪蕾伊小姐进行她第一次任务
I am going with Mistress Rey on her very first mission.
我已经做过了
I already have?
接收讯号 谁的讯号
Picking up a signal? From whom?
空袭厄西格所需的所有情报
All the information you need for an airstrike on Exegol.
对 就差怎么去
Yeah, except how to get there.
看这些大气读数
Are you seeing these atmo readings?
那里好乱
It's a mess out there.
磁场一片混乱
Magnetic crossfields.
重力井 太阳风
Gravity wells, solar winds.
舰队要如何从那里起飞
How does a fleet even take off from there?
真是抱歉
Terribly sorry.
R2的记忆库
I'm afraid Artoo's memory bank
一定被逻辑接受器干扰
must be crossed with his logic receptors.
他说他收到卢克主人传的讯号
He says he is receiving a transmission from Master Luke.
那是旧的飞机编号
That's an old craft ID.
那是卢克天行者的X翼战机
That's Luke Skywalker's X-wing.
它正传输航道标记讯号
It's transmitting course marker signals
到未知领域
on its way to the Unknown Regions.
是蕾伊
It's Rey.
她要去厄西格
She's going to Exegol.
她在指示我们
She's showing us.
指示我们如何前往
She's showing us how to get there.
那我们一起去
Then we go together.
走吧 兄弟 我们需要你
Come on, buddy, we need you.
只要驱逐舰群在厄西格上就能攻击
As long as those Star Destroyers are on Exegol we can hit them.
如何攻击
Hit them how?
它们离开大气才能启动护盾
They can't activate their shields until they leave atmosphere.
那么大的战舰需要协助才能起飞
Which isn't easy on Exegol. Ships that size need help taking off.
导航系统无法分辨方向
Nav can't tell which way's up out there.
所以那些战舰怎么起飞
So, how do the ships take off?
它们利用导航塔的讯号
They use a signal from a navigation tower,
像这个
like this one.
只是它们不会收到
Except they won't.
空中部队找导航塔
Air team's gonna find the tower,
地面部队轰炸它
ground team's gonna blast it.
地面部队 我已经想好了
Ground team? I have an idea for that.
一旦导航塔受损 舰队就困在大气中
Once the tower's down, the fleet will be stuck in atmo...
没有护盾 没有出路
for just minutes, with no shields, and no way out.
我们认为射击大炮
We think hitting the cannons
可能炸掉主反应器
might ignite the main reactors.
那是我们的机会
That's our chance.
我们得采用何朵策略
We need to pull some Holdo maneuvers.
造成重大损害
Do some real damage.
拜托 那项策略成功机率太小
Come on. That move is one in a million.
若人数够 战机与运输机能摧毁大炮
Fighters and freighters can take out their cannons if there are enough of us.
我们人数不足
没错 我们对他们不构成威胁
He's right. We'd be no more than bugs to them.
所以蓝多和丘伊能派上用场
That's where Lando and Chewie come in.
他们驾驶千年隼到核心星系
They'll take the Falcon to the Core Systems.
向外发出求救讯号
Send out a call for help for anybody listening.
我们在宇宙中有朋友
We've got friends out there.
他们觉得有希望就会前来
They'll come if they know there's hope.
他们会来的
They will.
让我们以为孤立无援 第一军团就赢
First Order wins by making us think we're alone.
我们并非孤立无援
We're not alone.
只要我们挺身而出 人们就会跟上
Good people will fight if we lead them.
莱娅从未放弃
Leia never gave up.
我们也不会
And neither will we.
让他们知道我们不害怕
We're gonna show them we're not afraid.
我们父母亲的反抗行动
What our mothers and fathers fought for...
不能在我们手中停止
we will not let die.
今天不行
Not today.
今天 我们做出最后一搏
Today, we make our last stand.
为了银河系
For the galaxy.
为了莱娅
For Leia.
为了我们失去的每个人
For everyone we've lost.
他们夺走我们太多了
They've taken enough of us.
现在我们直接向他们宣战
Now we take the war to them.
她逐渐接近
She's on approach.
全体船舰升至部署高度
All ships rise to deployment altitude.
我知道这趟飞行很不稳
I know it's a rough ride...
尽量维持在蕾伊的航线上
but stay locked on Rey's course.
频率畅通
Clear run frequency.
上尉 有抵抗势力船舰接近
Captain, we have Resistance craft incoming.
忠诚将军
Allegiant General...
发射离子炮
Use ion cannons!
你们看那支舰队
Look at that fleet.
可恶
Damn it!
欢迎来到厄西格
Welcome to Exegol.
注意右舷 卫斯理
Watch your starboard, Wexley!
到达他们的高度
Whoa! Get to their altitude.
他们射击我们也会伤到彼此
They can't fire on us without hitting each other.
别放弃
Don't give up.
支援马上到
Help is coming.
在那里
There it is.
波 我看到了
Poe, I see it.
我看到导航塔
I've got a visual on the tower.
钛战机来了 我看到了
Incoming TIEs! I see 'em!
我掩护你 芬恩
I got you, Finn.
准备好了吗 百分之百
You ready back there? Never been readier.
他们的目标是导航塔
They're targeting the navigation tower...
想让舰队无法部署
so the fleet can't deploy.
那我们就不用导航塔
Then we won't use that tower.
改从这艘船发射导航讯号
Switch over the source of navigation signal to this ship.
我们自己引导舰队
We'll guide the fleet out ourselves.
导航塔停用了
The navigation tower has been deactivated.
什么 那些船需要讯号
What? Those ships need that signal.
它一定来自某个地方
It's gotta be coming from somewhere.
他们猜中了我们的意图
They figured out what we're doing.
取消地面入侵
Call off the ground invasion.
等等
Wait.
导航讯号来自那艘指挥舰
The nav signal's coming from that command ship.
那就是我们的降落区
That's our drop zone.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
感觉
A feeling.
你想对灭星者驱逐舰发动地面入侵
You wanna launch a ground invasion on a Star Destroyer?
不想 但无法
I don't want to, but we can't take out
从空中破坏导航系统
that ship's nav system from the air.
掩护我们
Give us cover.
我们得把舰队困在那里等待支援
We gotta keep that fleet there till help arrives.
希望如此 希望如此
We hope. We hope.
你们听到将军的话了
You heard the General.
全体战机 掩护登陆艇
All Wings, cover that lander.
他们有一架运兵机降落
They've landed a troop carrier.
拦截飞行器 没办法 长官
Jam the speeders. I can't, sir.
为什么
Why not?
他们不是用飞行器
They're not using speeders.
只上一堂课就这么厉害
Not bad for one lesson.
是你的老师太会教
You had a good teacher!
继续吧
Keep going!
你表现得很好 老弟
You're doing great, buddy!
导航塔在前方
The tower's up ahead.
我等了好久
Long have I waited.
等我孙儿回家
For my grandchild to come home.
我从来就不要你死
I never wanted you dead.
我要你到这里来
I wanted you here...
帕尔帕廷女皇
Empress Palpatine.
你将接掌王位
You will take the throne.
你天生就有权统治这里
It is your birthright to rule here.
它在你的血液里 我们的血液
It is in your blood. Our blood.
我不是来领导西斯
I haven't come to lead the Sith...
而是来歼灭他们
I have come to end them.
以绝地武士的身份
As a Jedi?
- 是 - 不
- Yes. - No.
你的恨意 你的愤怒
Your hatred, your anger.
你想杀死我
You want to kill me.
那正是我要的
That is what I want.
杀了我
Kill me...
我的灵魂将进入你体内
and my spirit will pass into you.
既然全体西斯存在于我体内
As all the Sith live in me...
你会成为女皇
you will be Empress...
我们将合为一体
we will be one.
战况真激烈 情形如何
Those thrusters are hot. How are we doing?
我们一路轰炸 摧毁导航塔
We're gonna blow our way in, and take out that nav tower.
所有舱门都是防爆的
All the hatches are blast-proof!
BB-8 该你上了
All right, BB-8, you're up!
我掩护你
I'll cover you.
这应该可以
This should do it.
行了
There it goes.
做得好 芬恩
Nice one, Finn.
导航讯号失灵 但不会太久
Nav signal's down, but not for long.
我们离线了 长官
We're offline, sir.
重设导航讯号
Reset the navigation signal!
需要几分钟 长官
Minutes away, sir.
芬恩 我们走 等等 你听
Finn, let's go! No, no, wait, listen.
船顶的炮停了
The crown cannons have stopped.
他们在重设系统
They're resetting their systems.
所以呢 我得做一件事
So? I gotta go do something.
我留下来陪你
I'm staying with you.
千年隼和支援还是没来
Still no Falcon or backup.
不晓得 R2 说不定没人会来
I don't know, Artoo. Maybe nobody else is coming.
怎么办 将军
What do we do, General?
我们得自己攻击他们了
We gotta hit them ourselves.
要如何对付这些家伙
What can we do against these things?
想办法活下去
Just stay alive!
时候到了
The time has come!
满怀恨意的你将取我性命
With your hatred, you will take my life.
你会登上王位
And you will ascend.
你只要我恨 但我不会
All you want is for me to hate, but I won't.
连你都不恨
Not even you.
软弱 跟你父母一样
Weak. Like your parents.
我父母很坚强
My parents were strong.
他们从你手中救了我
They saved me from you.
你的卢克天行者导师 被他父亲拯救
Your Master, Luke Skywalker, was saved by his father.
你在这里唯一的家人
The only family you have here...
是我
is me.
他们时间不多
They don't have long.
没有人会来救他们
No one is coming to help them.
带他们来这里的人是你
And you are the one who led them here.
杀了我 登上王位
Strike me down. Take the throne.
统治新帝国
Reign over the new Empire...
舰队就任你差遣
and the fleet will be yours.
只有你拥有拯救他们的力量
Only you have the power to save them.
要是拒绝 你的新家人
Refuse, and your new family...
只有死路一条
dies.
很好
Good.
芬恩 你在哪里 登陆艇要离开了
Finn, where are you? The lander's leaving.
芬恩 别等我们了
Finn! Go without us.
我们要摧毁这整艘船
We're taking this entire ship down.
什么 怎么做
What? How?
我们会攻击指挥甲板
We're gonna hit the command deck.
萝丝 拜托 快走
Rose, please. Go.
萝丝 萝丝
Rose! Rose!
我去拿启动器
I'll get the trigger!
仪式开始
The ritual begins.
她将杀了我
She will strike me down...
宣誓成为西斯战士
and pledge herself as a Sith.
她将拿出武器
She will draw her weapon.
她将来到我面前
She will come to me.
她将展开报复
She will take her revenge.
她的光剑一挥
And with a stroke of her saber...
西斯便获得重生
the Sith are reborn!
绝地武士已死
The Jedi are dead!
动手
Do it!
做出牺牲
Make the sacrifice!
一起反抗 一同赴死
Stand together, die together.
你们联合起来的生命力
The lifeforce of your bond...
就是原力的二元体
a dyad in the Force.
如同生命般的力量
A power like life itself.
许多世代以来前所未见
Unseen for generations.
现在
And now...
两人的力量能使一个真皇帝复活
the power of two restores the one, true Emperor.
史耐普 他们在你后面
Snap, they're on your tail.
我看到了
Yeah, I see 'em!
不 不 史耐普
No, no, no, Snap, Snap!
不
No!
A3被击落
Alpha Three is down.
它们跟在我后面 我不能
They're on my tail! I can't get...
它们到处都是
They're everywhere!
三角中队队长受攻击
Delta leader's hit!
失去高度
Losing altitude!
将军 下一步怎么办
General, what's our next move?
波 怎么办
Poe, what now?
我的朋友
My friends...
对不起
I'm sorry.
我以为我们有机会
I thought we had a shot.
它们数量实在太多了
But there's just too many of them.
可是我们还有更多 波
But there are more of us, Poe.
我们还有更多人
There are more of us.
你看看
Look at this.
蓝多 你成功了
Lando, you did it. You did it!
攻击舰底炮
Hit those underbelly cannons.
摧毁一个能救一次世界
Every one we knock out is a world saved.
飞得真漂亮 蓝多
Nice flying, Lando.
有船受攻击 失去一艘驱逐舰
We have a ship down. We lost a Destroyer.
系统没反应
Systems not responding.
哪来这些战斗机
Where did they get all these fighter craft?
他们又没有海军
They have no navy.
那不是海军 只是平民
It's not a navy, sir, it's just people.
再见了 太空垃圾
So long, sky trash!
那个飞行员是谁
Who's that flyer?
猜猜看 香料走私贩
Take a guess, spice runner.
佐丽 你来了
Ha! Zorii! You made it!
看看你们造就了什么
Look what you have made.
就像我曾倒下
As once I fell...
最后的天行者也会殒落
so falls the last Skywalker.
不要惧怕那软弱的攻击
Do not fear that feeble attack...
我的信徒
my faithful.
什么都无法阻止西斯回归
Nothing will stop the return of the Sith!
R2 我系统失灵了
Artoo, my systems are failing.
有人收到吗
Does anyone copy?
与我同在
Be with me.
这些是你最后的步骤 蕾伊
These are your final steps, Rey.
起身行动
Rise and take them.
- 蕾伊 - 蕾伊
- Rey. - Rey.
蕾伊
Rey.
恢复平衡 蕾伊 像我一样
Bring back the balance, Rey, as I did.
在夜里 找到光 蕾伊
In the night, find the light, Rey.
你并不孤单 蕾伊
You're not alone, Rey.
孤单 你从来都不是
Alone never have you been.
史上每个绝地武士都活在你身上
Every Jedi who ever lived lives in you.
原力包围着你 蕾伊
The Force surrounds you, Rey.
让它引导你
Let it guide you.
一如它引导我们
As it guided us.
感受原力贯穿全身 蕾伊
Feel the Force flowing through you, Rey.
让它扶起你
Let it lift you.
起来 蕾伊
Rise, Rey.
我们支持你 蕾伊
We stand behind you, Rey.
蕾伊
Rey.
起身于原力中
Rise in the Force.
绝地武士的信念是她的力量
In the heart of a Jedi lies her strength.
- 起来 - 起来
- Rise. - Rise.
蕾伊 原力将永远与你同在
Rey, the Force will be with you, always.
让你的死成为反抗故事中
Let your death be the final word...
最后的句点
in the story of rebellion.
我恢复正常了 这是最后机会
I'm back on! This is our last chance.
我们快攻击那些炮
We gotta hit those cannons now!
你微不足道
You are nothing!
拾荒者女孩完全比不上我的力量
A scavenger girl is no match for the power in me.
我是全能的西斯大帝
I am all the Sith!
而我
And I...
我是全部的绝地武士
I'm all the Jedi.
波 指挥舰
Poe, the command ship!
他们的舰队困在这里了
Their fleet is stuck here!
他们被击中了 快啊
They're toast! Come on!
芬恩 你看到了吗
Finn, you seeing this?
芬恩没登上登陆艇
Finn didn't board the lander.
他们还在那艘指挥舰上
They're still on that command ship?
我看到他们了 我去接他们
I see them. I'm going to get them.
将军 你赶不上的
General, you won't make it.
相信我 我很快
Trust me, I'm fast!
没有这艘船快
Not as fast as this ship.
抓稳了 丘伊
Hold on, Chewie!
芬恩
Finn!
不 蕾伊
No, Rey.
班
Ben.
那边 看
There, look!
红队五号升空了
Red Five is in the air.
蕾伊还活着
Rey's alive.
我看见她了
I see her.
全银河系的人民纷纷起义
People are rising up all over the galaxy.
波 我们成功了
Poe. We did it.
我们成功了
We did it.
开心
Happy.
丘伊
Chewie!
嗨
Hi!
做得好
Good job!
丘伊
Chewie.
这是给你的
This is for you.
你听见了吗
Did you hear that?
你来自哪里 将军
Where are you from, General?
黄金星系
The Gold system.
你呢 孩子
Well, what about you, kid?
我不知道
I don't know.
那我们去找答案
Well, let's find out.
好久以来都没有人来过
There's been no one for so long.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是蕾伊
I'm Rey.
蕾伊什么
Rey who?
蕾伊天行者
Rey Skywalker.